import Header from "./Header";
import Error from "./Error";
import Main from "./Main";
import Question from "./Question";
import { useReducer, useState } from "react";
import StartScreen from "./StartScreen";
import CompletedQuiz from "./CompletedQuiz";

const initialState = {
  questions: /*[
    {
      question: "Let's start easy: Gabriel's favorite color: ",
      options: ["Red", "Blue", "Grey", "Magenta"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "Gabriel's favorite artist",
      options: ["Eminem", "50 Cent", "Kwengface", "Tzanca Uraganu'"],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "Let's get racist: Race Gabriel hates most",
      options: ["Italians", "French", "Swiss", "Gipsies"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "We had our first proper kiss in 2018. Which date",
      options: ["10 August", "16 August", "20 September", "22 August"],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "What's Gabriels favorite sport to watch?",
      options: ["Football", "Basketball", "Stone skipping", "None"],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "What does Gabriel love most about you?",
      options: ["Personality", "Soul", "Eyes", "Boobies ðŸ¤¤"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "What was the name of the book he made you",
      options: [
        "Indescribable bond",
        "Unbelievable bond",
        "Indestructible bond",
        "Unmatchable bond",
      ],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question: "Gabriel's dreams in order",
      options: [
        "Get some experience as F.E. developer, build his own business, invest in real estate",
        "Get some experience as F.E. developer, build multiple mini businesses, invest in real estate",
        "Die working for Dr. Colasanti ðŸ’€",
        "Get some experience as F.E. developer, build his developing related business, marry you, invest together in real estate",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question: "Physical part of you Gabriel loves most",
      options: [
        "Feet",
        "Boobies ðŸ¤¤",
        "Booty",
        "None, cause he doesn't give a shit about physical stuff",
        "Cake a.k.a your gorgeously lovely most beautiful in the world nose",
      ],
      correctOption: 4,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question:
        "You consider Gabriel as a long term relationship with eventual marriage worthy partner?",
      options: [
        "Who? This guys with 0 rizz? Nah, man, I'm good",
        "You must be taking the piss",
        "Meh, I've met better",
        "YES! You may now kiss!",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 30,
    },
  ]*/ [
    {
      question: "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
      options: ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "Which company invented React?",
      options: ["Google", "Apple", "Netflix", "Facebook"],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "What's the fundamental building block of React apps?",
      options: ["Components", "Blocks", "Elements", "Effects"],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question:
        "What's the name of the syntax we use to describe the UI in React components?",
      options: ["FBJ", "Babel", "JSX", "ES2015"],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "How does data flow naturally in React apps?",
      options: [
        "From parents to children",
        "From children to parents",
        "Both ways",
        "The developers decides",
      ],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "How to pass data into a child component?",
      options: ["State", "Props", "PropTypes", "Parameters"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question: "When to use derived state?",
      options: [
        "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
        "Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
        "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
        "Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question: "What triggers a UI re-render in React?",
      options: [
        "Running an effect",
        "Passing props",
        "Updating state",
        "Adding event listeners to DOM elements",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question: 'When do we directly "touch" the DOM in React?',
      options: [
        "When we need to listen to an event",
        "When we need to change the UI",
        "When we need to add styles",
        "Almost never",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 20,
    },
    {
      question: "In what situation do we use a callback to update state?",
      options: [
        "When updating the state will be slow",
        "When the updated state is very data-intensive",
        "When the state update should happen faster",
        "When the new state depends on the previous state",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "If we pass a function to useState, when will that function be called?",
      options: [
        "On each re-render",
        "Each time we update the state",
        "Only on the initial render",
        "The first time we update the state",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which hook to use for an API request on the component's initial render?",
      options: ["useState", "useEffect", "useRef", "useReducer"],
      correctOption: 1,
      points: 10,
    },
    {
      question:
        "Which variables should go into the useEffect dependency array?",
      options: [
        "Usually none",
        "All our state variables",
        "All state and props referenced in the effect",
        "All variables needed for clean up",
      ],
      correctOption: 2,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question: "An effect will always run on the initial render.",
      options: [
        "True",
        "It depends on the dependency array",
        "False",
        "In depends on the code in the effect",
      ],
      correctOption: 0,
      points: 30,
    },
    {
      question:
        "When will an effect run if it doesn't have a dependency array?",
      options: [
        "Only when the component mounts",
        "Only when the component unmounts",
        "The first time the component re-renders",
        "Each time the component is re-rendered",
      ],
      correctOption: 3,
      points: 20,
    },
  ],
  //"loading", "error", "ready", "active", "finished"
  status: "ready",
  index: 0,
};

function reducer(state, action) {
  switch (action.type) {
    case "start":
      return { ...state, status: "active" };
    case "reset":
      return { ...state, index: 0, status: "ready" };
    case "next":
      if (state.index === state.questions.length - 1) {
        console.log("finished");
        return { ...state, status: "completed" };
      } else {
        console.log("still going");
        return { ...state, index: state.index + 1 };
      }
    default:
      throw new Error("Action unknown");
  }
}

export default function Quiz() {
  const [{ questions, index, status }, dispatch] = useReducer(
    reducer,
    initialState
  );
  const [score, setScore] = useState(0);

  const numQuestions = questions.length;

  return (
    <div className="quiz">
      <Header />

      <Main>
        {status === "ready" && (
          <StartScreen
            numQuestions={numQuestions}
            onStart={() => dispatch({ type: "start" })}
          />
        )}
        {status === "active" && (
          <Question
            question={questions[index]}
            questionNr={index}
            length={questions.length}
            onNext={() => dispatch({ type: "next" })}
            score={score}
            setScore={setScore}
          />
        )}
        {status === "completed" && (
          <CompletedQuiz
            score={score}
            maxScore={questions.reduce(
              (acc, question) => acc + question.points,
              0
            )}
            onReset={() => {
              setScore(0);
              dispatch({ type: "reset" });
            }}
          />
        )}
      </Main>
    </div>
  );
}
